# Nicholas Kammer, CPA

Estero, FL | kammer@gmail.com | Github: https://github.com/ScroogesMoneybin | Website: NAEK2.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Detail-oriented researcher/programmer with experience in financial and investment assets, management, investment banking, mergers & acquisitions, valuations, data analysis. Interested in programming, data science, and finance.

Computer/Data Analytics programming experience in Javascript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Python, SQL, R, Tableau, and LLMs.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **MIT**

MicroMasters program in Statistics and Data Science - Online

University of Pennsylvania 2019 - 2021
Master of Arts in Near Eastern Languages & Civilizations GPA 4.00/4.00

May 2004 GPA:3.97/4.00

2021 - Present

## University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Master of Science in Accountancy

Awards: Phi Kappa Phi

Brown University
Bachelor's degrees in Mathematics, Mathematical-Economics, and Egyptology
GPA: 3.81/4.00

**Awards:** Magna cum Laude Phi Beta Kappa

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Owner and Website Developer**

Acceptionally.com

Online e-commerce site storefront for Nancy's Boutique

- o Nancy's Boutique is an online multi-platform retail storefront, selling clothing and household items
- Nancy's Boutique also distributes through Amazon, eBay, and Facebook Marketplace in addition to Acceptionally.com
- Built with ReactJS site using Redux and Redux Saga on the front-end and utilizes a Netlify serverless functions for deployment
- Processes payments through Stripe Payment Element
- Incorporates Google Firebase and Firestore database
- Includes Progressive Web App (PWA) functionality

Professor 2021 - 2022

Ave Maria University

- Professor of Accounting
  - o Taught Managerial Accounting
  - Oversaw student projects designing their hypothetical businesses and building Master Budgets
  - Created PowerPoint presentations for each topic covered and posted them to Canvas website for easy access
  - Assisted AMU's career services in networking with local businesses to expand job opportunities for graduates
  - o Advised Business School administration on enhancing the undergraduate data analytics program
    - Advised about the appropriate programming tools and languages to emphasize to improve student job placement
    - Researched opportunities to expand in-class learning tools from Tableau
  - Utilized Microsoft Teams to tutor students who could not attend regular in-person meetings or tutoring

- Professor of Mathematics
  - o Taught College Algebra and Calculus for over 150 students at a time
  - Advised students on outside classes (such as computer programming) to give themselves the best career opportunities
  - Created PowerPoint presentations for each topic covered and posted them to Canvas website for easy access
  - o Held lengthy sessions outside office hours and class for tutoring and make-up quizzes and exams
  - Utilized Microsoft Teams to tutor students who could not attend regular in-person meetings or tutoring
- Counseled students with career planning advice
- Mentored students on Javascript

# **Private Investment Analyst and Trader**

2017 - Present

- Managed portfolio of stock and option trades to maximize profits
- Evaluated investment vehicles with emphasis on growth opportunities
- Utilized databases and chart analysis to analyze investment data to select best opportunities
- Manage private trust assets for the benefit of beneficiaries
- Researched new opportunities, including:
  - o Private company angel investments for clients
  - o Advised on the potential of developing exotic asset opportunities for clients

#### NAEK2, LLC

Valuation Consultant 2008 – 2015

- Worked as a consultant, analyzing start-up companies early in development, especially at the Research Park connected with the University of Illinois' entrepreneur incubator
- Prepared financial statements and projections for the purposes of strategic planning, presentations to awards committees, and recruitment of potential investors
- Performed valuations for companies to determine fair valuations in negotiations with investors, utilizing methods such as:
  - Market-based valuation
  - o Discounted cash flow
  - o Closely-held business valuation
  - Minority ownership discounting

#### **Dresner Partners Investment Bank**

2004 - 2008

Analyst

- Worked primarily in Mergers and Acquisitions on the sell side
- Developed valuation models such as NPV, LBO, and market comparables to determine fair value of client companies for sale negotiations
- Recruited businesses as clients on the sell side
- Researched and recruited potential buyers for client companies

### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

#### NAEK2.com

- Personal website
- Contains selection of Javascript, ReactJS, Typescript, and Solidity projects

# **Generative AI Document Analysis App**

- Document analysis tool written in Python, utilizing Langchain, Chroma vector database, and Generative AI Large Language Model (one version with ChatGPT and another version with Google's Bard AI)
- Allows user uploading of personal documents for analysis
- User can ask questions of the AI about the document
- Adjustable parameters available to give more or less detailed AI responses
- Link to apps is on personal website under Projects: naek2.com

### **Launched Private Blockchain Network**

- Utilized geth to initialize and launch private blockchain on the Goerli test network of Ethereum
- Created Externally Owned Account
- Initiated mining for the private blockchain

# Dispersion Study of Book of the Dead Spells using Tableau

- Utilized Tableau to track and investigate the geospatial and temporal diffusion of spells from the Book of the Dead in Ancient Egypt
- Mapped the sources of every object with Book of the Dead spells by specified criteria using Tableau's geolocation features
- Cross-analyzed the artifacts by time period, location, gender of the owner, and quantity.
- Performed trend analysis through the time periods to see how dispersion developed chronologically

# **Develop Database of Ancient Egyptian Coffin Texts**

- Compiled, digitized, and cleaned over 6,000 lines of data on funerary texts from old, out-of-print research compendiums to allow broader access to researchers
- Joined data from multiple databases into a broader database for more efficient analysis as .csv and Excel files
- On-going process
  - o Current work has been on data from only one time period
  - Database will be expanded to include funerary texts from across multiple time periods, including the Pyramid Texts of the Old Kingdom, the Coffin Texts of the Middle Kingdom, and the Book of the Dead from the New Kingdom and Ptolemaic Period

## Classification of MNIST Digits and Multi-digits using Python

- Implemented a variety of data science methodologies in Python to study the famous MNIST database and compare methodologies as applied to the database
  - Neural networks both manually built and utilizing PyTorch
    - Fully Connected Neural Network
    - Convolutional Neural Network
  - Support Vector Machine for multiclass classification
  - o Softmax regression with gradient descent
- Successfully tuned hyperparameters of convolutional neural network using PyTorch to achieve 98.02% accuracy for test set of multi-digit dataset

#### PROFESSIONAL CREDENTIALS AND AFFILIATIONS

- Certificates in computer programming from ZTM Coding Academy in Javascript, React, Node, Golang, and Network Security
- Registered CPA
- AICPA member since 2004
- Personal Financial Specialist (PFS)
- CANSLIM investing certification
- Foundations of Data Science (Professional Certificate) University of California, Berkeley Online

# **OUTSIDE INTERESTS**

Alumni interviewer for Brown University applicants